reliablesoft.net 2019-05-08

# Privacy Policy - reliablesoft.net

Revised: May 23, 2018

Reliablesoft.Net is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the Reliablesoft.Net Web site and governs data collection and usage. By using the Reliablesoft.Net website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

## Collection of Personal Information

Reliablesoft.Net collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. Reliablesoft.Net also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by Reliablesoft.Net. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by Reliablesoft.Net for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Reliablesoft.Net Web site.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

## Newsletter

The newsletter is run on our own servers. Your email address and name will never be shared. It is a double opt in service (meaning after subscribing you will need to confirm by email) and each email sent to you will provide an unsubscribe link.

## Use of Personal Information

Reliablesoft.Net collects and uses your personal information to operate the Reliablesoft.Net Web site and deliver the services you have requested. Reliablesoft.Net also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Reliablesoft.Net and its affiliates. Reliablesoft.Net may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

Reliablesoft.Net does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. Reliablesoft.Net may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Reliablesoft.Net may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Reliablesoft.Net, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Reliablesoft.Net does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

Reliablesoft.Net keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within Reliablesoft.Net, in order to determine what Reliablesoft.Net services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within Reliablesoft.Net to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

Reliablesoft.Net Web sites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Reliablesoft.Net or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Reliablesoft.Net; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Reliablesoft.Net, or the public.  

## Use of cookies

The Reliablesoft.Net Web site use “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Reliablesoft.Net pages, or register with Reliablesoft.Net site or services, a cookie helps Reliablesoft.Net to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Reliablesoft.Net Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Reliablesoft.Net features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Reliablesoft.Net services or Web sites you visit.

 **Google Ads and DART**

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.  
Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Reliablesoft.Net public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: Reliablesoft.Net does not read any of your private online communications.

Reliablesoft.Net encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from Reliablesoft.Net so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. Reliablesoft.Net is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the Reliablesoft.Net and Reliablesoft.Net family of Web sites.

 **Google Analytics  **

Currently we are using Google Analytics to analyze the audience of the website and improve our content. No personal information is collected from Google Analytics. For further information on the privacy policy concerning Google Analytics, please go here: [http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/analytics/privacyoverview.html](http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/analytics/privacyoverview.html)

## Security of your Personal Information

The personal information collected from the visitors of our website, including their identity, remains confidential. We respect the law(s) on confidentiality applicable to this website (United States) and we will never pass on these data to any third party, unless required by law. Our website does not collect any cookies.

Reliablesoft.Net secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Reliablesoft.Net secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## What data we collect when you create purchase a product from us

We collect information about you during the checkout process on our store.

What we collect and store  
While you visit our site, we’ll track:

Products you’ve viewed: we’ll use this to, for example, show you products you’ve recently viewed  
Location, IP address and browser type: we’ll use this for purposes like estimating taxes and shipping  
Shipping address: we’ll ask you to enter this so we can, for instance, estimate shipping before you place an order, and send you the order!  
We’ll also use cookies to keep track of cart contents while you’re browsing our site.

When you purchase from us, we’ll ask you to provide information including your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, phone number, credit card/payment details and optional account information like username and password. We’ll use this information for purposes, such as, to:

Send you information about your account and order  
Respond to your requests, including refunds and complaints  
Process payments and prevent fraud  
Set up your account for our store  
Comply with any legal obligations we have, such as calculating taxes  
Improve our store offerings  
Send you marketing messages, if you choose to receive them  
If you create an account, we will store your name, address, email and phone number, which will be used to populate the checkout for future orders.

We generally store information about you for as long as we need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it, and we are not legally required to continue to keep it. For example, we will store order information for 5 years for tax and accounting purposes. This includes your name, email address and billing and shipping addresses.

We will also store comments or reviews, if you choose to leave them.

 **Who on our team has access**  
Members of our team have access to the information you provide us. For example, both Administrators and Shop Managers can access:

Order information like what was purchased, when it was purchased and where it should be sent, and  
Customer information like your name, email address, and billing and shipping information.  
Our team members have access to this information to help fulfill orders, process refunds and support you.

## Payments

We accept payments through PayPal and 2checkout. When processing payments, some of your data will be passed to PayPal and 2checkout, including information required to process or support the payment, such as the purchase total and billing information.

## Changes to this statement

Reliablesoft.Net will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. Reliablesoft.Net encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Reliablesoft.Net is protecting your information.

## Contact Information

Reliablesoft.Net welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Reliablesoft.Net has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Reliablesoft.Net at webmaster@Reliablesoft.Net. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
